powershop.com.au 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy - Powershop Australia

This privacy policy tells you about the way we, Powershop, collect information, use it, and if we disclose it, who we disclose it to.

##### The Gist

We're a customer-focused company, and that means we care about your privacy. In providing services to you we need to collect some personal information, and sometimes (as set out below) it's necessary to disclose that information to others (such as the government and regulatory bodies).

##### Website

This website is operated by Powershop Australia Pty Limited ABN 41 154 914 075 ( ** _Powershop_** ) under the domain name www.powershop.com.au. This policy refers to all activities of Powershop, and references to 'us', 'we' and 'our' in this policy are references to Powershop and its related bodies corporate, their contractors and agents.

##### Privacy Act

The  _Privacy Act 1988_  (Cth) (the  ** _Act_** ) sets out Australian Privacy Principles (the  ** _Principles_** ) and we are committed to upholding those Principles.

The Principles are designed to protect the confidentiality of information and the privacy of individuals by regulating the way personal information is managed. Personal information is information about an individual which can be used to identify that individual (such as names, addresses, telephone numbers, date of birth, etcetera).

##### Collection of Personal Information

When we collect your personal information we will normally provide you with information about how and why we are collecting the information. You can view our general policy on the [collection of personal information](https://www.powershop.com.au/collection-statement/) for more information.

##### What information we collect and how we collect it

In providing services Powershop may collect and hold personal information about you and your property. Powershop may collect information directly from you (including through our agents such as telemarketers), from our website (including through our customer live-chat application), and from third parties who are involved in your electricity supply (such as your distribution company or metering data provider). We may collect information in a variety of ways, such as through promotions, surveys, recordings of customer calls, sales calls, customer tickets, posts on our blog, from a credit reporting agency, etcetera.

We manage sensitive information with particular care, including information on racial and ethnic origin, political opinion, political association membership, religious beliefs and affiliations, philosophical beliefs, professional and trade association membership, trade union membership, sexual preferences or practices, criminal record, or health information. We will obtain your consent prior to collecting, using or disclosing your sensitive information, unless the collection of the information is required by law.

##### Use of your information

The information we hold about you and your property will be used to provide our services to you and for related purposes, for example:

  * confirming your identity;
  * supplying you with electricity and other services you have requested;
  * carrying out credit checks or otherwise assessing your creditworthiness. See our [credit reporting policy](https://www.powershop.com.au/credit-reporting-policy/) for more information;
  * communicating with you;
  * complying with our obligations to you and other third parties involved in the supply of electricity to you and your property;
  * receiving payments and debt collection;
  * improving customer service;
  * providing you with information on third party products and services; or
  * for our general business purposes (such as aggregating customer consumption information to track trends) or corporate purposes (such as financing, reporting, sale or purchase of businesses etcetera).

Powershop will not sell, lend, trade or otherwise disclose your personal information to any other person or agency except as set out in this policy.

##### Disclosure of your information

Powershop will not share your personal information, except when:

  * you tell us we can do this;
  * we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law;
  * we want to carry out a credit check to consider your credit worthiness. See our [credit reporting policy](https://www.powershop.com.au/credit-reporting-policy/) for more information;
  * we need to do so to manage the provision of energy to you or it is a matter covered by our customer contract;
  * we want to keep you informed about products or services;
  * we want to recover money from you when you have not paid us, or if we want to list any payment defaults with a credit agency;
  * you are switching to another energy retailer;
  * the distribution company needs or has requested the information. Some examples of when we may do this are if the information is to help supply energy or to distribute money on their behalf; or this is necessary to assist an adjudicator to resolve a complaint you make about us; or
  * we need to do so for general business purposes (such as aggregating customer consumption information to track trends) or corporate purposes (such as financing, reporting, sale or purchase of businesses etcetera).

After you cease to be a customer we will still use your personal information for our general business purposes (such as in aggregated consumption data), to call you if you switch away in order to finalise your account and get your feedback, and if you owe us money we will use your personal information to recover money from you or to take action in relation to a payment default in accordance with our credit reporting policy. If we no longer require your personal information for any of the purposes for which it was collected we will then take all reasonable steps to destroy your personal information or ensure that your personal information is de-identified.

Other than as outlined above, we will not share your information with anyone else. We will not share information about the account with anyone living at the property, except if they are also named on the account.

##### Accessing your personal information

You may ask us for access to any personal information we hold about you. If you think that information is inaccurate or incorrect, you may ask us to consider correcting or deleting it from Powershop’s database. You can do this by sending an email to the following address: [info@powershop.com.au](mailto:info@powershop.com.au). We may deny your request in circumstances where it is reasonable to do so. If we do this, we will tell you why.

If at any time you wish to stop receiving information about new products or services you may do this by sending an email to the following address: [info@powershop.com.au](mailto:info@powershop.com.au).

##### Storage and security of personal information

We will keep personal information secure. Most personal information will be held in our customer application which is stored and processed in Australia and New Zealand. However, some personal information will be held in physical files at our offices or electronically in our computer network. Our staff members have unique user identifications and passwords. We work to ensure that our staff members understand all of their and our responsibilities under the Act. Our physical premises are protected by reasonable security precautions. We do use some services which involve the transfer, processing and storage of some personal information (for example, our customer live-chat application and global messaging platforms) outside of Australia, including New Zealand, the United States of America and the European Economic Area. These services are likewise protected by unique user identifications and passwords. In respect of those customers who sign up via an overseas aggregator, we may share personal information, for general business and corporate purposes, with such aggregators, in countries including South Africa and the Philippines. Information disclosed to such overseas aggregators will be transmitted securely.

##### Email

Sometimes we send our customers information. We may do this by email. You will receive some information exclusively by email, such as notification about energy you have used, or notification under our customer terms. We may also send you by email newsletters or other information we think you may be interested in. Newsletters and other information you receive will have instructions as to how you can remove yourself from that mailing list. If you ask to be removed from a mailing list, we will do this.

##### Your username and password

If you are a Powershop customer, you are responsible for appropriately protecting your username, email address and password. Your username and password can only be used in connection with purchasing products for the supply of energy to your property or properties. You should not tell anyone else your password or username, and if you do, you are responsible for paying for any energy they may buy from us.

##### Card security

When you use your credit card on our website (www.powershop.com.au), the credit card information is transmitted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. This encrypts your information. Powershop keeps only some of your credit card details. However your full credit card details will be encrypted and securely stored by our online payment provider (currently Direct Payment Solutions) and, from time to time, by parties we engage who provide similar data encryption and storage services.

Make sure you always logout when you have finished using the Powershop customer website, especially if you access Powershop from a shared computer.

##### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information stored on your computer. Cookies help us improve your user experience when you use our websites. The technology we use mostly uses 'session' cookies. Session cookies expire after 30 minutes of no activity on the Powershop website. However, some cookies we use for internet statistics or remarketing last longer.

Cookies cannot damage files, contain no personally identifiable information and cannot read information from the hard drive of a computer. It is possible to disable the acceptance of cookies by your web browser. However, doing so may restrict your ability to access some web pages.

We may use Google Remarketing as a method of targeting our advertising. We may also use similar services from other providers from time to time which have similar appropriate privacy policies in place. Remarketing is a way for us to connect with visitors, based upon your past interactions with Powershop's website. As a result, third-party vendors, including Google, may use cookies to show Powershop ads to you as you visit third party sites on the internet.

You have the option to opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page:[http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

Alternatively, you can opt out of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>.

See the section on ‘Information we collect from Google Analytics’ below to find out the sorts of things we use the cookies to track.

##### Information we collect from Google Analytics

Powershop currently uses standard Google Analytics tools and cookies in its website and mobile applications. We may use similar services from other providers from time to time which have similar appropriate privacy policies in place. Google Analytics collects a range of information such as the number of visitors on our site per day, which pages they visit, their computer’s internet protocol address and operating systems, visit times, browser type and language, referring website addresses and the types of devices using our websites and mobile applications. We use this information to analyse trends, to better configure our service and messages, to track the performance of our mobile applications and referring websites, to administer our website and apps and to monitor your interactions with our website and apps. When Google Analytics receives personal information, that information is transferred, processed and stored on Google servers around the world by Google in accordance with Google’s privacy policy: <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>.

##### Other information we collect

We collect other information to help us understand how our sites are working and how we could improve it and/or our services. This may include URLs of pages you visit or have visited, which operating system and browser you are using, your IP address, and the date and time of your visit.

While we may publish aggregated information of this sort, we will not publish information about individual machines, and we only disclose and use it as set out in this policy. This includes disclosing it to the Police or other Government authorities if we think we are obliged to by law.

We collect and may keep any information you post in messages to our customer website or Blog, or feedback through our mobile applications.

If you decide to try to sign up to become a Powershop customer and you enter your contact details but you do not successfully complete the sign-up process, we may contact you to see if we can help you finish signing up and/or to get your feedback. If we do this, we will use the personal details you have entered on the sign up page to contact you.

If you download and use our mobile applications we collect and use information obtained through them to help us understand how customers are using them, to diagnose problems and for the other purposes set out under 'Use of your information' above. This information includes the name and brand of your mobile device, the operating system of your phone and the version of that operating system, the screen resolution, your current Powershop customer number, the unique device key, user agent (browser) and IP address. We also use Google Analytics tools in our mobile applications: see the section 'Information we collect from Google Analytics'.

We may gather more extensive information if we are concerned, for example, about abnormal website usage patterns or website security breaches.

##### Complaints

If at any time you feel that we have not complied with this policy or the Australian Privacy Principles please let us know and we will take reasonable steps to investigate such matters. You can do this by sending an email to [complaints@powershop.com.au](mailto:complaints@powershop.com.au) or by writing to us at:  
Powershop  
PO Box 1639  
Melbourne VIC 3001  
C/ – Contact Centre Manager

The way in which we deal with complaints is set out on our website at: [www.powershop.com.au/complaints/](https://www.powershop.com.au/complaints/).

##### Changing this policy

We may change this policy at any time. We will tell you about changes by posting an updated policy on our website. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on privacy practices at Powershop.

If you have any questions about our privacy policy or any other matter, please contact us.

* This Privacy Policy was published on 18 February 2019 and replaces all previous Powershop Privacy Policies.
